Guide to the Margaret Strickland Papers 1880-1963 MSS.077
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV: Diaries, Ephemera, Scrapbooks
  Series IV: Diaries, Ephemera, Scrapbooks comprises bound and unbound memento materials, calendars, collected images and newsprint clippings of interest, collected and original poetry, correspondence, day to day domestic records, drawings and notation, event invitations that range from artistic performances to weddings, gardening awards from the Royal Horticultural Society, photographic portraits and postcards of loved ones, printed and published works, and traces of Strickland family history.
  Printed ephemera.; Notebooks.; Printed materials.; Printed ephemera.; Manuals.; Souvenir programs.; Theater programs.; Photography of dogs.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photography of cats.; Newspapers.; Black-and-white photographs.; Portrait photography.; Diaries; Scrapbooks.; Clippings (information artifacts); Clippings (information artifacts); Notes.; Signatures (binders' notations).; Guidebooks; Calendars.; Account books.; Picture postcards.; Postcards.; Photographic prints.; Photography of children.; Portrait photography |z Great Britain.; English poetry |y 19th century.; Poetry.; Drawings; Watercolors (paintings); Programs (documents); Invitations.; Advertisements.; Memorabilia.; Commercial correspondence.; Legal documents.; Crossword Puzzles; Formulas, recipes, etc.
  - Awards & Prizes, 1932 September 2-3; 1942 - 1944; 1952 December 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    5 Grenfell Metal Certificates for Achievements in Botanical Arts with 2 Horticultural Prizes
    Recipients: “Miss [Agnes] Strickland”; “Mrs. [Margaret Strickland] Worley”
    Grantors: “Honorable Secretary J.M. Risdon, 71 Maryland Road, N.22 - for the Eleventh Annual Show of The London Allotments & Gardens Show Society, The Royal Horticultural Hall, Westminster, SW [London, England]”; Royal Horticultural Society; “The Maldens & Coombe Horticultural Society, Raynes Park, London [England] SW”
    In Reference To: Botanical Arts / Drawings / Flowers / Gardening / Watercolor Painting
    7 Card Certificates, Unbound
    Measurements: 6.25” x 4.75” - 9” x 6”
  - [Book of Poetry]: “Sonnet”, undated, circa 1912 - 1916 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    1 Fragmented Personal, Unpublished Booklet with Collected / Original Poetry
    62 Pages, Bound by String with No Cover
    Measurements: 4.5” x 7”
  - Book of Poetry with Inscription, undated, circa 1888 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Toynbee, William.Song-Words. Simpkin Marshall & Company with R&A Spalding: London, England. Undated, circa 1888. [With Inscription & "A Southern Serenade" from Toynbee]
    56 Pages, Bound & Unbound
    Measurements: 4.5" x 7" - 6.5" x 8"
  - Diary: “Charles Letts & Company Diary & Notebook MDCCCXII”, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Owner: “Margaret Worley, Cornwall, Brentwood, Essex, [England]”
    Features: Advertisements, Calendar, Cash Account Charts, Daily Wants’ Dictionary, Personal Memoranda, Phone Numbers
    Approximately 400 Pages
    Bound with Maroon Cover
    Measurements: 2.75” x 4”
  - Diary: “The Boots Chemists Home Diary and Ladies’ Note Book”, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Owner: “Margaret Worley, 88 Alderson Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1]”
    Features: Addresses, Advertisements, History of Sir Jesse Boot & Boots Chemists, Jewish Calendar, Legal Generalities, Memoranda, Postal & Savings Bank Regulations, Sundry Accounts
    Approximately 350 Pages
    Bound with Blue Cover
    Measurements: 4.75” x 7.25”
  - Ephemera with Notation, 1897 November 27 - 1960; undated, circa 1912 - 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    [Assorted Scrapbook Materials]
    1 Christina Rossetti Calendar [Blank], Flower Making Lists; Funeral Card “Eliza Emma Strickland”; "I wrote a letter to my love" Sketch by Agnes Strickland; Landscape Photograph; National Registration Card; Newsprint Clippings about Agnes & Margaret Strickland; Poetry Inscription for Loyal Richard Penderell [Copy]; Printed Materials; Royal Warrants for Photography Cards; Scrapbook Pages; “The London Opera House” Program Fragment; "The Times" London Marriage Announcements Card featuring Richard Hugh Worley & Margaret Strickland Union; Worley-Strickland Wedding Invitation
    19 Pages, Bound & Unbound
    Measurements: 3” x 5.5” - 9” x 13.5”
  - Exhibition Catalogue, Summer 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Pope-Hennessy, Una. "Biography of the Queens of England [for the] Centenary of the Queens of England 1840-1940 by Agnes Strickland, Exhibition in aid of the British Red Cross, Presented at 477 Oxford Street, London, [England] by Mr. J & E. Bumpus Limited, Booksellers to His Majesty The King.” Chatto & Windus: [London, England]. Summer 1940.
    16 Pages, Bound & Printed
    Measurements: 4” x 5”
  - Legal Record, 1916 October 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    1 Publishing Agreement “As To ‘The Elusive Peg’ ” with Postage [Not Signed]
    Grantee: “Margaret [Strickland] Worley, 88 Alderney Street, Victoria SW, Westminster, [London, England]”
    Grantor[s]: “Directors Harry L. Angold & Stan Wood of Angold’s Limited, 10 Bolt Court Street, London, [England]”
    In Reference To: Business / Financial / Writing; Witnesses [Edward G. Robert of Stock Exchange W.C.] & "L.W. Dethier, 10 Bolt Court”
    5 Pages, Bound by String
  - Scrapbook: "Album", 1893 July 8 - 1902 April (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Owner: [Margaret] “Maggie Strickland”
    Features: Images of Animals (Cats), Landscapes, People, Portraits - Ink Drawings, Printed Materials, Watercolor Paintings; Musical Notation, Newsprint Clippings, Poetry [Collected / Original] / Poetic Notation from Friends, Pressed Plants
    Approximately 100 Pages
    Unbound with Red Cover
    Measurements: 3.5” x 4.5”
  - Scrapbook: “Album”, 1893 December 7 - 1897 January 20 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    [Owner: Margaret Strickland]
    Features: Images of Animals (Cats & Dogs), Landscapes, People, Portraits - Photographs, Ink Sketches, Printed Material, Watercolor Paintings; Musical Notation, Poetry, Notation, Recipes, Signatures of Agnes Strickland, Amila Patrickson, Amy Prichard, Amy Thyme, Annie Neild, Beatrice Sidney William, C. Grant, Dolly Wilson, Edith M. Porter, Ethel Houlder, Ethel Richardson, Gladys [Courtney], Grace Patrickson, G. Webster, Hannah F. Corke, Hetty Atkinson, H. Stafford Webb, "Maggie" [Margaret] Strickland, Mary Main, Nora Price, W.K. Thyme
    Approximately 200 Pages
    Unbound with Black Cover
    Measurements: 6” x 7”
  - Scrapbook: "A Very Remarkable Publisher" with Ephemera, 1900 February 25 - 1960 August 9 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Features: English Post Card; Envelope with Postage; Images of Animals (Cats & Dogs), Flowers, Landscapes, People, Plants, Portraits, Seascapes - Hand-Colored Sketches, Ink Drawings, Photographs, Newsprint Clippings, Watercolor Paintings; Notation, Poetry, Pressed Flowers & Plants
    Measurements: 7” x 9”
  - Scrapbook: “Newspaper Cuttings,” Ephemera, Professional Correspondence, Source Materials, 1898 November 4 - 1962 May 20 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    [Scrapbook Owner: Margaret Strickland]; 2 Letters with Notation, 1 Post Card with Postage
    Addressed To: “[Margaret] Strickland 88 Alderney Street, [South Belgravia], London, [England] SW1”
    Sent From: “[A.E. Leroy], Book Department of Country Life London, 20 Tavistock Street, Covent Garden, London, [England] WC2, Telephone - Temple Bar 7351”; “Emmie” [of Unidentified Location]
    In Reference To: Animals / Business / Friendship / Personal / Professional / Writing; Manuscript Notes, Synopsis Review
    [Scrapbook] Features: 3 Post Cards [Blank]; Crossword Puzzles; Images of Animals (Cats & Dogs), Children, People, Portraits - Ink Drawings, Magazine Clippings, Newsprint Clippings, Photographs, Printed Materials; Musical Performance Program Fragments; Notation; Source Materials for Children's Story featuring Cats; “The Ivory Cross Journal” Clippings
    Bound & Unbound with Blue & Black Cover
    Measurements: 9.5” x 11”
  - Strickland Family Crest, undated, circa 1897 - 1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    2 Ink & Watercolor Renderings: “Strickland Coat of Arms, Sans Mal”
    Handdrawn & Painted in Ink & Pencil
    Measurements: 7.5” x 10.5”
- Series V: Photographs
  These materials are arranged alphabetically by subject category, then chronologically if applicable. In the case that a record includes more than one date expression, the listing will begin with its earliest. If a record is physically undated, approximate ranges are provided. These records are noted "undated" and followed by a "circa" estimate determined by the range represented in the same series or record file.
  Series V: Photographs includes black and white prints of group portraits, mounted individuals' portraits, pocket and postcard portraits of men, women, children, and animals, interior design and exterior snapshots of estate gardens and grounds, and travel images. This series features a group portrait at Margaret Strickland and Richard Hugh Worley's wedding, as well as images from Richard's childhood and education at the University of Cambridge.
  Notes.; Photography of women.; Personal papers.; Correspondence.; Photography of dogs.; Photography of young men.; Cambridge, England.; Black-and-white photographs.; Photography of men.; Photography of sports.; Photography of cats.; London, England.; Photography of interiors.; Photographs; Landscape photography.; Picture postcards.; Photographic prints.; Portrait photography.; Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Photography of children.; Portrait photography |z Great Britain.
  - [Interiors], undated, circa early 20c (Box 9, Folder 2)
    4 Photographs Featuring Home Furnishings & Design
    Black & White Prints, Unbound
    Mounted on Cardstock
    Measurements: 6” x 4” - 10” x 8”
  - [Outdoor Scenes], 1931 April 28; undated, circa 1900 - 1920 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    6 Photographs Featuring Exteriors / Estate Design, Leisure with Dogs & Sports Competitions [Running]; Male Nude in Nature
    Mounted on Cardstock by “Stearn, 72 Bridge Street, Cambridge, [England]”
    Measurements: 8.75” x 6.5” - 10” x 8”
  - [Portraits: Men], undated, circa early 20c (Box 9, Folder 4)
    7 Portraits of Men in Formal Wear & Military Uniform
    Mounted on Cardstock by: “Chesney Limited, 50 Strand, London, [England] WC”; “Elliot & Fry, 55 Baker Street West, London, [England]”; “G. West, Godalming & Haslemere”; “Karl Schenker, 1 Dover Street, London, [England] W1”
    Measurements: 6.5” x 7.75” - 7.5” x 10.75”
  - [Portraits, Postcards, Snapshots], 1914; 1934 December 3; undated, circa 1900 - 1940 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    32 Photographs with Notation:
    Post Cards & Snapshots Featuring Exteriors / Gardens, Leisure with Dog & Portraits [Men & Women]
    Black & White Prints with Hand-Coloring, Unbound
    Portraits & Postcards / Mounted on Cardstock by "Chesney Limited, 50 Strand 395 Oxford Street West [London, England]"; "H.J. Whitlock & Sons Limited, Birmingham, Wolverhampton, Cardiff, [England]"; "Jerome Limited; Los Angeles Portrait Studios 75 Princes Street, Edinburgh, [Scotland]"; “Mora, 127 Western Road, Brighton, [England]”; "Relph & Company 130 Church Street, Preston, [England]"; “Stearn, Cambridge, [England]”; "USA Studios in London & Provinces, [England]" Measurements: 1.75” x 3” - 6.25” x 4.5”
  - [Portraits, Postcards, Snapshots], 1917 January; 1932 July 15; 1963; undated, circa early 20c (Box 9, Folder 6)
    38 Photographs with Notation:
    Post Cards, Pocket Portraits [Cat, Children, Dog, Men, Women] & Snapshots Featuring Exteriors / Gardens, Home Interior Design; Leisure At Sea & In Transit
    Portraits & Postcards Mounted on Cardstock by / of: “Bodger the Cat, Bred by Margaret Strickland”; [Cathedrals of Venice, Italy]; “H.J. Whitlock & Sons, Limited, Photographers to the King, Birmingham, Wolverhampton, Cardiff [England]”; “Jerome, Limited, 182 Kings Cross Road [London, England] WC1”; “Leroi, Limited 524 & 526 Oxford Street West, [London, England]”; “Mercer Hatch, London Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”; “Schuth’s Photographic Galleries, 16 Piccadilly, London [England]”; “W. Bates & Son, Chertsey, [Surrey, England]”
    Measurements: 2.5” x 3” - 5.5” x 10.75”
  - [Portraits: Women], undated, circa early 20c (Box 9, Folder 7)
    7 Portraits of Women in Formal Wear & Swimwear
    Mounted on Cardstock by:“F.A. Swain Limited, 8 Clifford Street, New Bond Street West [London, England]"; “Franz Baum, 22 St. Ann’s Square, Manchester, London Studio 12 Old Bond Street West & Studio For Equestrian Portraits & Company, Winton House, Bowdon [England]”; “Lambert Weston & Son, 27 New Bond Street West [London, England]”
    Measurements: 6.25” x 8.25” - 8” x 10”
  - Disbound photographic album, ca. early 20th century (Box 11)
    Group photographs, sporting photographs, tourist alpine photographs, etc.
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Diaries, Ephemera, Scrapbooks
  - Education Certificates with Ephemera, 1890 June; 1897; undated, circa 1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    2 Local Examinations in Music Certificates with "A New Card Game 'The Sport of Kings or King of Sports' " Handwritten List of Derby Winners
    Grantee: "Margaret Strickland in Pianoforte Playing"
    Grantor[s]: "Chairman of the Board Thomas Threlfate, Director of Royal College of Music A.C. Mackenzie & Principal of Royal College of Music C. Hubert H. Parry with The Associated Board Of The Royal Academy of Music & The Royal College of Music, President His Royal Highness The Prince of Wales, K.G. at Tunbridge Wells [Kent, England]"; "[Instructor] Mr. W.W. Starmer with Academic Board of Tunbridge Wells, Trinity College, London [England]"
    Measurements: 11" x 9" - 9.25" x 13"
  - Strickland Family Tree, undated, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
    "Pedigree Of Agnes Strickland" from the Westminster Public Library with Notation
    Measurements: 20" x 8"
- OVERSIZE Series V: Photographs
  - [University of Cambridge: Dinner Party], 1897 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    1 "October Term" Group Portrait with 7 Men Including:
    "E.C. Miller, Honorable L.M. St. Aubyn, J.H. Gibbon, J.L. Bailey, O.B. Pease, Richard Hugh Worley"
    Black & White Print with Handpainted Crest
    Names & Event Title Handwritten in Ink
    Measurements: 17" x 13"
  - [University of Cambridge: Dinner Party], undated, circa 1897 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    1 Group Portrait with 10 Men Including Richard Hugh Worley
    Black & White Print
    Mounted on Cardstock by "R.H. Lord, Market Street, Cambridge, [England]"
    Measurements: 18" x 13"
  - [University of Cambridge: Group Portrait Outdoors], undated, circa 1897 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    1 Group Portrait [Men & Women] Including Richard Hugh Worley with 2 Architectural / Garden Images
    Black and White Prints
    Mounted on Cardstock by "Stearn, Cambridge [England]"
    Measurements: 12.5" x 10.5"
  - [Wedding: Group Portrait Outdoors], undated, circa 1908 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    1 Margaret Strickland & Richard Hugh Worley Wedding Portrait with Group of 9 [Men & Women]
    Mounted on Cardstock by "G. Herrett, Brentwood, [England]"
    Measurements: 15" x 12"
  - "West Wratting Park the House" [Group Portrait Outdoors], 1896 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    1 Group Portrait of 29 [Adult & Child, Men & Women] Including Richard Hugh Worley at West Wratting, Cambridge
    Black and White Print
    Event Title Handpainted
    Measurements: 16.5" x 13"
  - "West Wratting Park [the] House" [Group Portrait Outdoors], 1897 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    1 Group Portrait of 34 [Adult & Child, Men & Women] Including Richard Hugh Worley at West Wratting, Cambridge
    House Crest & Event Title Handpainted
    Mounted on Cardstock by "R.H. Lord, Cambridge, [England]"
  - [Young Male Sports Team Portrait], undated, circa 1890 - 1896 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    1 Group Portrait of 11 Young Men Including Richard Hugh Worley
    Mounted on Cardstock by "Godalming & Haslemere, [England]"